<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<Menu>

  <Image url="https://barotraumagame.com/gamedata/HalloweenPackBanner.png" relativesize="0.15,0.21" minsize="200,158" pivot="BottomLeft" relativeoffset="0.3,0.64"/>
   <!--<Image url="https://barotraumagame.com/gamedata/HalloweenPackTextBlock.png"/>-->
    
  <GUIListBox anchor="TopRight" ishorizontal="false" relativeoffset="0.02,0.015" relativesize="0.25,0.8" childanchor="TopRight" style="null">
    <Accordion text="Official Halloween mod pack out now!" relativesize="1.0,0.06" style="GUISlopedHeader">
      <GUIFrame resizetofitchildren="true" relativeresizescale="1.05,1.2" relativesize="1.0,1.0" style="TextFrame" anchor="TopRight">
        <GUILayoutGroup ishorizontal="false" resizetofitchildren="true" relativesize="0.9,0.9" anchor="Center" relativespacing="0.02">
          <Text relativesize="1.0,0.0">Download here:</Text>
          <Link relativesize="1.0,0.0" url="https://www.google.com/" style="MainMenuGUIButton">Download now</Link>
        </GUILayoutGroup>          
      </GUIFrame>
    </Accordion>
    <spacing relativesize="1.0f, 0.01"/>
    <Accordion text="v0.9.4.0 changelog:" relativesize="1.0,0.06" style="GUISlopedHeader">
      <GUIFrame resizetofitchildren="true" relativeresizescale="1.05,1.0" relativesize="1.0,1.0" style="TextFrame" anchor="TopRight">
        <GUILayoutGroup resizetofitchildren="true" relativesize="0.9,1.0" anchor="Center" childanchor="TopCenter">
          <Text relativesize="0.95,0.0" color="255,255,255,255">\nMonster additions and changes:</Text>
          <Text relativesize="0.95,0.0" font="smallfont">
- New character: Bonethresher.
- New character: Golden Hammerhead.
- Completely remade the Tigerthresher (new skin, ragdoll, behavior and attacks).
- Reworked Hammerhead (new ragdoll, adjusted behavior and attacks).
- Adjusted the behavior of most characters.
- Medium sized monsters can now more easily trigger impact effects when ramming the submarine.
- Characters are now allowed to move faster than previously (increased max speed from 9 to 15 m/s).
- Changed the mouth position calculations and redefined the values for all monsters that have the eating behavior.
- Removed Moloch Baby (Which was just a test. Molochs will be revisited later).
- Better bend deformations on limbs.
- Better feedback about hit impacts on limbs when the character takes damage.
- AI monsters should hit moving targets more easily.
- Added configurable health regeneration, which is applied when the character is eating a corpse.
- Added configurable affliction reductions (bleeding, burn, damage).
- Added an option for the monsters to ignore retaliation when they are attacked.
- Added an option to target the attack on specific limb types.
- Added an option to continue the movement, "following through" the target after the attack.
          </Text>
          <Text relativesize="0.95,0.0" color="255,255,255,255">Modding improvements:</Text>
          <Text relativesize="0.95,0.0" font="smallfont">
- Mods can override specific content without having to create a completely new content package. This can be done by surrounding the element with "override" xml elements (for example, an Item or a Character config element you want to replace a vanilla Item/Character with). The overrides work based on identifiers; for instance, if you configure an item with the identifier "wrench" and surround it with the override tags, it will replace the vanilla wrench.
- Content package load order: the game will first load the core package, then other content in the order  of selection (proper ui still pending). The load order is saved in the config_player.xml.
- Made AI orders and event manager settings moddable.
- The engine and reactor sound ranges can now be modified in the item XML.
- The husk affliction can now be modified and applied on any character.
- Support for multiple simultaneous husk afflictions based on the same system.
- Support for multiple husk appendages. Made the attachment limb configurable in the affliction definition.
- Additional content package validity checks during startup: make sure all XML files in the package can be loaded, and disable the package if they can't. Fixes tons of console errors on startup when a mod with invalid XML files is enabled.
- Don't allow publishing workshop items that contain invalid XML files.
- Don't allow selecting invalid content packages in the settings menu.
- Fixed disabled content packages becoming active when they're autoupdated.
          </Text>
          <Text relativesize="0.95,0.0" color="255,255,255,255">Character editor improvements:</Text>
          <Text relativesize="0.95,0.0" font="smallfont">
- Improved layout, hotkeys, general UI/UX improvements.
- Support for editing the character configuration files including health, ai, inventory, sounds, particles etc.
- Support for limb sounds.
- Support for light sources attached to limbs.
- Support for adding and removing attacks.
- Support for afflictions in attacks.
- Support for damage modifiers in limbs.
- New functionality: creating limbs (without having to operate on duplicates).
- Support for creating humanoids.
- Allow to create new characters based on an existing character (copy character).
- Added a limb specific "sprite orientation" that overrides the universal "spritesheet orientation".
- Option for mirroring limb sprites.
- Option for hiding the limb sprite (invisible limbs).
- Multiple minor additions and changes, like an option to enable lights or to display the damage modifiers drawn on the character.
- Exposed structure sound types.
- Exposed the mouth position.
- Exposed the angular damping and density for limbs (removed mass, which was not used).
- Added a default texture path for ragdolls so that the texture can only be defined once. Limb specific texture definitions override this.
- Allow to define a group for different species. The characters in the same group are friendly to each other.
- DecorativeSprites can now be used on character limbs (like on items).
- Made it easier to adjust the source rect's position with the arrows. Hold CTRL to change the size.
- Fixed a rare case where characters got stunned in the character editor.
          </Text>
          <Text relativesize="0.95,0.0" color="255,255,255,255">Misc improvements:</Text>
          <Text relativesize="0.95,0.0" font="smallfont">
- New husk faces.
- Increased default VOIP and microphone volume and the maximum values.
- Force a restart when switching the language.
- More detailed "x is not a valid XML file" error messages.
- Improved mission and traitor info popups.
- Show the number of lights (total and shadow-casting) in the sub editor.
- When rewiring, clicking the right mouse button only removes one node from the wire.
- Wire nodes are added by left clicking in the sub editor, and can be laid out horizontally/vertically by holding shift.
- Improved logging for DXGI_ERROR crashes on startup.
- Made level ambient lighting darker.
- Added "pause" console command (only usable in single player).
          </Text>
          <Text relativesize="0.95,0.0" color="255,255,255,255">Bugfixes:</Text>
          <Text relativesize="0.95,0.0" font="smallfont">
- Fixed crashing when the recharge speed of a PowerContainer with no interface (e.g. Alien Generator) is adjusted by a signal or a bot.
- Fixed docking interface becoming active on navigation terminals when any of the submarine's docking ports are close to another docking port, even if the terminal in question is not wired to that port.
- Fixed an occasional crash when a bot starts retreating away from an enemy immediately after spawning.
- Fixed clients not creating a download prompt when a sub they don't have is selected by vote.
- Fixed traitor missions almost always placing the mission-related items inside the same containers.
- Fixed traitor goal durations being displayed as "duration(xx) seconds" instead of "xx seconds".
- Fixed Traitor's "find an item" objectives not being considered complete if the target item is inside another item within the traitor's inventory.
- Fixed server using the provided campaign savefile name as-is (without the required .save file extension) when starting a new campaign through the console. Caused clients to throw "File transfer failed (wrong file extension """!)" errors and prevented them from receiving the save files.
- Fixed servers being able to start the round multiple times by spamming the "start" console command before loading the round finishes.
- Fixed rewiring sound playing whenever a remote player is using a rewireable device.
- Fixed subinventories not opening when grabbing another character with no items in the corresponding slot.
- Fixed draggable inventories getting stuck to a half-open state if the item is equipped when the inventory is opening/closing.
- Fixed light sprites being mirrored when the item is mirrored, even if the mirroring the item's sprite had been disabled (e.g. junction boxes).
- Fixed motion sensor detection area not being flipped when the item is mirrored.
- Fixed status monitor not mirroring rooms on the display in mirrored subs.
- Fixed engine propeller position not being flipped when the item is mirrored.
- Fixed diving suits being displayed in an incorrect position when the locker has been flipped on either axis.
- AI characters turn autotemp back on when leaving the reactor.
- Fixed item sprites becoming unmirrored when a damaged sprite is fading in.
- Fixed damaged item sprites that are set to fade in according to the damage always being drawn at full opacity.
- Fixed spectators being distributed into teams in combat missions, potentially leading to imbalanced crew sizes.
- Notify the client using the "togglekarmatestmode" command about the test mode being enabled/disabled.
- Send karma change notifications when karma has changed by 1 unit or more when test mode is enabled, not just when an action causes an immediate change of 1 unit or more.
- Fixed adjacent sprites bleeding into the platform and topwindow sprites.
- Fixed autocompleting submarine/shuttle names when using the submarine/shuttle console commands.
- Fixed some items (like sonar beacon) attracting monsters even when they're powered off.
- Fixed inability to open the pause menu if an inventory slot had been highlighted when exiting the game screen.
- Fixed welded door sprites "twitching" when the submarine moves.
- Fixed crashing when a character with no hands or arms drops a holdable item.
- Non-humanoids (i.e. monsters controlled by a player) cannot be assigned as traitors.
- Traitor missions are considered unsuccessful if the objectives cannot be completed (for example if the submarine doesn't have suitable containers to place the traitor items inside).
- Fixed the "Barotrauma" title text staying invisible in the main menu when coming back from the credits.
- Fixed clients not refreshing an item's editing hud when a remote player adjusts the values (i.e. if two players had selected the same lamp and one changed the color value, the other client wouldn't see the value change in the editing hud).
- Fixed a couple of the additive light sprites being slightly offset from the lamp.
- Clients don't display client-side vitality changes in healthbars until the actual vitality is received from the server. Fixes health occasionally dropping and then jumping back up if the client predicts damage incorrectly (e.g. if a melee attack hits client-side but doesn't server-side).
- Fixed character syncing being very inaccurate when switching to freecam and spectating a character far away from other players.
- Fixed oxygen/fuel tanks attached to a tool being rendered behind the character's legs.
          </Text>
        </GUILayoutGroup>
      </GUIFrame>
    </Accordion>
  </GUIListBox>
</Menu>