<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<LoadingScreenTips language="English">

  <LoadingScreenTip>You will not get paid for delivering cargo if any of the cargo goes missing or gets damaged during the transport.</LoadingScreenTip>
  <LoadingScreenTip>Generating more power than the devices in the submarine are consuming may damage junction boxes or cause fires.</LoadingScreenTip>
  <LoadingScreenTip>Junction boxes and other electrical devices may get damaged if they stay submerged too long.</LoadingScreenTip>
  <LoadingScreenTip>Letting submarine's nuclear reactor overheat may cause fires. If an overheated reactor is not shut down, it will eventually lead to a nuclear meltdown.</LoadingScreenTip>
  <LoadingScreenTip>Most submarines are equipped with stationary batteries that can be used as a temporary source of backup power in the case of a reactor failure.</LoadingScreenTip>
  <LoadingScreenTip>Railgun shells and depth charges include a compartment that can hold additional explosives.</LoadingScreenTip>
  <LoadingScreenTip>Passive sonar can be used to detect nearby sound sources without attracting unwanted attention. You can also get a rough idea of your surroundings based on the sounds reflected from the ice walls.</LoadingScreenTip>
  <LoadingScreenTip>There are many ways to get past locked doors, including forcing them open with a crowbar or rewiring them to a button you have access to.</LoadingScreenTip>
  <LoadingScreenTip>Stationary batteries are equipped with docks that can be used to charge battery cells.</LoadingScreenTip>
  <LoadingScreenTip>Oxygen generators are equipped with docks that can be used to refill oxygen tanks.</LoadingScreenTip>
  <LoadingScreenTip>Supercapacitors can deliver large bursts of power, but cannot store as much energy as batteries. They are often used to power railguns and other devices that require brief bursts of high current.</LoadingScreenTip>
  <LoadingScreenTip>Nuclear reactors are equipped with an automatic control system that adjusts the power output to a suitable level when enabled. However, the system is not always fast enough to react to large fluctuations in power consumption.</LoadingScreenTip>
  <LoadingScreenTip>The sonar imaging on the navigation terminal may become inaccurate if the terminal is damaged - make sure your engineers keep the terminal in a good condition!</LoadingScreenTip>
  
  <LoadingScreenTip>Attempting to rewire powered devices without adequate electrical engineering skills may get you electrocuted.</LoadingScreenTip>
  <LoadingScreenTip>Welding tools are simple enough to be used by any submariner, but trained mechanics are generally faster welders and have a lower risk of injuring themselves with the tool.</LoadingScreenTip>
  <LoadingScreenTip>All submariners have been trained to do basic repairs on electrical devices, but electrical engineers get the job done much faster.</LoadingScreenTip>
  <LoadingScreenTip>All submariners have been trained to do basic repairs on mechanical devices, but mechanics get the job done much faster.</LoadingScreenTip>
  <LoadingScreenTip>Captains are generally much more adept at manouvering the submarine than the average sailor.</LoadingScreenTip>

  <LoadingScreenTip>Breaking down alien artifacts in a deconstructor may provide you with exotic raw materials.</LoadingScreenTip>  
  <LoadingScreenTip>Special caution must be taken when bringing alien artifacts on board the submarine.</LoadingScreenTip>
  <LoadingScreenTip>Some of the alien structures on Europa have been constructed of a metamaterial that's outstandingly resistant to physical damage, and as such has become an important subject of research to Europan scientists.</LoadingScreenTip>
  <LoadingScreenTip>Special caution must be taken when bringing alien artifacts on board the submarine.</LoadingScreenTip>
  <LoadingScreenTip>Very little is known of the presumably extinct alien civilization that built the ruins scattered all across Europa. The age of the ruins is also a mystery, since the self-repairing properties of the structures and devices make chronological dating methods wildly inaccurate.</LoadingScreenTip>
  <LoadingScreenTip>No remains of the alien lifeforms that built the ruins scattered all across Europa have ever been discovered. The only life encountered inside the structures are the biomechanical entities that maintain and guard them.</LoadingScreenTip>

  <LoadingScreenTip>The cephalopod-like watchers are generally docile, but may attack when provoked.</LoadingScreenTip>
  <LoadingScreenTip>Cannibalistic behavior is very common among crawlers. Killing one in a swarm may distract the rest as they enter into a feeding frenzy.</LoadingScreenTip>
  <LoadingScreenTip>Mud raptors can easily tear their way through metal doors with their sharp beak.</LoadingScreenTip>
  <LoadingScreenTip>The so-called husk parasites slowly take over and consume the body of their host, eventually turning them into nothing but an empty exoskeleton controlled by the parasite.</LoadingScreenTip>
  <LoadingScreenTip>Many creatures on Europa are protected by a strong shell, and are difficult to damage with conventional weapons unless hit from below.</LoadingScreenTip>
  <LoadingScreenTip>Loud devices and sonar pings may alert nearby creatures.</LoadingScreenTip>
  
  <LoadingScreenTip>Performing CPR without adequate medical skills may cause internal damage to the patient.</LoadingScreenTip>
  <LoadingScreenTip>Opiates such as morphine and fentanyl are an effective way of treating injuries in an emergency, but regular use may eventually lead to a state of addiction and cause dangerous withdrawal symptoms.</LoadingScreenTip>
  <LoadingScreenTip>Morbusine is a neurotoxin potent enough to take down even some of the largest Europan predators. A trained medical doctor can manufacture it relatively easily using a medical fabricator.</LoadingScreenTip>
  <LoadingScreenTip>Bleeding wounds can be treated with bandages and hemostatic agents. The patient may also need saline or blood packs to replace the lost blood.</LoadingScreenTip>
  <LoadingScreenTip>Mental disorders such as psychosis are unfortunately common among submarine crews, particularly after ruin expeditions. If your crewmates start seeing or hearing things others don't see or hear, report it to a medical doctor immediately.</LoadingScreenTip>
  <LoadingScreenTip>The Medical Doctors' main task is to keep the crew in a good shape, but a medic with a syringe gun and a bit of knowhow on poisons can also be very useful in fending off intruders.</LoadingScreenTip>
  
  <LoadingScreenTip>When using a diving mask, be careful not to mix up welding fuel tanks and oxygen tanks.</LoadingScreenTip>
  <LoadingScreenTip>Diving masks let you breathe underwater, but don't offer any protection against the bone-crushing pressure outside the submarine. If there's a major hull breach, find a diving suit immediately.</LoadingScreenTip>
  <LoadingScreenTip>In the event of a fire, burns are not the only thing to watch out for - fires can quickly consume all the oxygen inside the submarine.</LoadingScreenTip>
  <LoadingScreenTip>Traversing the so-called Hydrothermal Wastes requires special caution. Not only are they abundant in wildlife, but the water currents caused by geothermal activity make navigation even more hazardous.</LoadingScreenTip>
  <LoadingScreenTip>Some of the sessile lifeforms in Europa emit low-frequency sounds that may disrupt the submarine's sonar.</LoadingScreenTip>
  <LoadingScreenTip>Be careful not to dive too deep. Most submarine hulls will start collapsing at the depth of approximately 2000 meters.</LoadingScreenTip>

  <LoadingScreenTip>You can disguise yourself as someone else by wearing their ID card and something that covers your face.</LoadingScreenTip>
  
  <LoadingScreenTip>It's possible to build voice-controlled systems by linking wifi components to the radio chat in the submarine editor.</LoadingScreenTip>

  <!-- Lore -->
  <LoadingScreenTip>The radiation belts around Jupiter make it impracticable to establish permanent settlements above Europa's surface, and as such almost all Europan outposts are located below its icy crust.</LoadingScreenTip>
  <LoadingScreenTip>The dynamics of Europa's underwater ecosystem are still not fully understood, but it is believed that the base of the food chain is mostly formed by chemosynthetic bacteria.</LoadingScreenTip>
  <LoadingScreenTip>The Europa Coalition started off as a trade and co-operation agreement between the two largest Europan settlements and a handful of private paramilitary groups, but gradually grew to become what is essentially the Europan government.</LoadingScreenTip>
  <LoadingScreenTip>The much-ridiculed initiative to help submariners cope in a high-stress environment by including professional entertainers in the crews was promptly deemed a failure and discontinued.</LoadingScreenTip>
  <LoadingScreenTip>Most vessels avoid venturing outside the tunnels and cracks within Europa's icy crust - the vast, empty Abyss between the surface layers and the rocky interior hosts many of Europa's largest and most dangerous inhabitants.</LoadingScreenTip>

</LoadingScreenTips>